

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Senior Quality Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Agile Development, Quality Engineering, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Unit Testing, API

Testing, Programming, Application Support, Docker, JSON, Java, SVN, AWS, Git

Current Designation: Senior Quality Engineer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Company: QualiTest Group Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Quality Engineer, Team/Tech Lead, Software Engineering, Software Development, Agile Development, Quality Engineering, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Unit Testing, API

Testing, Programming, Application Support, Docker, JSON, Java, SVN, AWS, Git

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21

Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Passionate and experienced Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in the industry. Adept in the field of Development, QE, DevOps and Test Architecture & Infrastructure. Worked to reduce Cost and Time to market for Test phase and Optimize QA process while evolving from QA to QE.

Proficient with Databases, CI/CD, Automation, API development and testing. In-depth understanding of Virtualization and Containerization. Aspiring to improve Quality Engineering as a domain

Work Experience

QualiTest Group as Senior Quality Engineer Aug 2018 to Till Date

Implemented Shift Left for multiple applications saving Time and Cost in the overall QA

Created organization wide standard, process and frameworks for quality

Created fully automated CI pipelines using Gitlab for continuous integration using Shell

Built Docker container images for language specific environments (java, php, dotnet, java script) improving CI workflow, increasing performance and optimizing speed of CI pipelines

Strategized and Implemented Contract Testing for pre-deployment testing

Actively worked on TDD development and Unit testing with Java, C# and JS Mgrated from traditional API testing techniques to Postman API automation for better CI/CD integration and reporting

Introduced code quality scans in the CI pipeline for improving code quality and reducing

Worked on version control tools like Git, SVN. Configured pipelines and jobs for them and created documents for setting up the infrastructure for the same

Worked on creating and configuring servers for testing using GCP and VMware Workstation

Have worked on Linux OS for Docker image creation and CI implementation code build, scan

Have worked on SSO testing. Used Samling for IDP'simulation to configure and test the application integration with over 10 IDP's including creating and configuring local servers to host IDP's

Leading a team of 4 for continuous delivery for the client on the above tasks

SPOC for complete task delivery and client DSR

Designed automation frameworks and standard for the team for further development and delivery

Cross trained and up skilled the team with the required technologies by proper planning and forecasting



Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Have conducted IDD training Hackathon for developers Conducted Interviews for the organization. Have actively participated in Client Demos Created assets for the organization for easier implementation of the tools and concepts across multiple projects

Replicon Software Pvt Ltd as Subject Matter Expert/Tier 3 Engineer Aug 2015 to Mar 2018

Created Utilities using Node.Js to perform custom Ad hoc tasks utilizing Web Services and API

Experienced with programming concepts like Asynchronous calls, Batch

Management, Multi-threading, Queuing, JSON conversions and parsing

Writing custom codes to identify issues, improve performance or perform scheduled tasks using Web Services and API

Assist customers in depth with their integration

Identify any DB issues causing application defect/bug and write scripts to fix them

Identify and address performance issues with Database

Restore and troubleshoot Database in a local environment to identify dependency or any other DB related issues in the application

Having knowledge on Views, OLAP and Database Management

Setting up Single Sign On for customers using SAML or OAuth

Worked with multiple IDP's Azure, Okta, Shibboleth, ADFS. Assist customers in setting up configurations specific to their business needs and organization infrastructure.

Set up SSO environment locally for requirement validation of customers

Used tools like SAML Tracer to identify issues and fix SSO

Highly familiar with tools like MS Excel, Chrome Developer tools, SumoLogic, Fiddler.

Heavily worked on Salesforce for Log management

Exposure to AWS. Creating Dynamic Swimlanes to host local instances of application for troubleshooting

IBM as Technical Support Engineer Jun 2014 to Jul 2015

Provided IT support to technical/non-technical personnel within the business Worked on resolving configuration issues for in-house applications like Lotus Notes, IBM Verse. ILC

Used ticketing systems to manage and process actions taken

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Manipal Institute of Technology (MIT) in 2014

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
DevOps, Java, JSON, Git, SVN	
Agile Development, Docker, AWS.	
Lotus Notes, MS Excel, PHP	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Maithili				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.